你  伊森  愿意娶茱莉亚为你的合法妻子吗
Do you, Ethan, take Julia to be your lawful wedded wife?
我愿意
I do.
相依相偎  相亲相爱  相敬相护
To have, to hold, to love, cherish, honor, and protect?
我愿意
I do.
去保护她免受已知和未知恐怖的侵害
To shield from terrors known and unknown?
-去撒谎  去欺骗...  -什么
- To lie, to deceive... - What?
去过双面生活  无法阻止她被绑架
To live a double life, to fail to prevent her abduction,
抹去她的身份  逼她隐于人世
erase her identity, force her into hiding,
-夺走她所知的一切  -停
- take away all she has known... - Stop.
-用自私  徒劳  暂时的方式  -停
- ...in a selfish, futile, fleeting attempt... - Stop.
来逃避你真正的自我
...to escape your own true self?
求你了  停下
Please, stop.
茱莉亚  你选择接受吗
And, Julia, do you choose to accept?
别
Don't.
-我接受  -不
- I do. - No.
你该杀了我的  伊森
You should have killed me, Ethan.
贝尔法斯特
命运对勇士低语
Fate whispers to the warrior...
风暴将至
A storm is coming.
勇士低声回应
And the warrior whispers back...
我即风暴
I am the storm.
荷马史诗
身份确认
伊森·亨特
晚上好  亨特先生
Good evening, Mr. Hunt.
无政府主义者所罗门·莱恩
The anarchist Solomon Lane.
自从你两年前抓捕他之后
Since you captured him 2 years ago,
他的消失带来了意料之外的后果
his absence from the world stage has had unintended consequences.
他曾领导的由变节特工组成的辛迪加组织
His Syndicate of rogue covert operatives
继续在全球范围内肆虐
continues to wreak havoc around the globe.
中情局特别行动科
The CIA's Special Activities Division
一直在坚持不懈地追捕莱恩的特工网络
has relentlessly hunted Lane's elite network of hostiles.
但还是有很多人未知或在逃
But many remain unknown and at large.
这个极端分裂组织剩余的成员
The remnants of this extremist splinter cell
自称「使徒」
refer to themselves as "The Apostles."
使徒
他们采取了"雇佣恐袭"策略
They have since adopted a policy of terror-for-hire,
让他们成为了更大的威胁
making them an even greater threat.
最近在印控克什米尔和中巴边界
They are responsible for the recent smallpox outbreak
爆发的天花疫情
in Indian-controlled Kashmir,
克什米尔
就是他们的手笔
along the borders of China and Pakistan,
全球三分之一的人口都受到了威胁
threatening one-third of the world's population.
疫情已经得到了控制
The epidemic is being contained,
但情报显示
but intelligence would indicate
已经有一个新客户雇佣了使徒
that a new client has hired the Apostles
来执行更庞大的行动
for a more ambitious operation.
此人曾联系过他们
They have been contacted by this man,
一个信息不详的极端分子
an unidentified extremist
约翰·拉克
只知其代号是"约翰·拉克"
known only by the code name John Lark,
他撰写了这份末日宣言
author of this apocalyptic manifesto
呼吁人们摧毁当前的世界秩序
calling for the destruction of the current world order.
所有的和平  都需要伟大的牺牲
据推测挪威核武器专家
It is believed Lark is responsible for the disappearance
尼尔斯·德布朗克的失踪就与拉克有关
of Norwegian nuclear weapons specialist Nils Delbruuk.
尼尔斯·德布朗克
德布朗克博士的安全权限
Dr. Delbruuk's security clearance was revoked
在他发表了极度反宗教言论后就被取消了
after he expressed fiercely anti-religious views.
与此同时  使徒一直和
Meanwhile, the Apostles have been in contact
使徒
东欧地下世界的成员有联系
with elements of the Eastern European underworld,
他们手中有三枚从俄罗斯东部
who are in possession of three plutonium cores
一个导弹基地偷取的三颗钚核
stolen from a missile base in eastern Russia.
这意味着约翰·拉克和使徒
This would indicate that John Lark and the Apostles
正在协作  试图获得可用的核武器
are working together to acquire functioning nuclear weapons.
核事件应急支援小组预计  以德布朗克的水平
NEST estimates that a man with Delbruuk's knowledge,
使用获得的材料
using the materials in play,
他可以在72小时内造出三枚核武器
could complete three nuclear weapons in as little as 72 hours.
这些装置将是手提式的
These devices would be man-portable
一夜之间就能被安放到世界的任意角落
and deployable anywhere on Earth overnight.
这些武器在约翰·拉克和使徒手里
In the hands of John Lark and the Apostles,
将对数以百万计的人
these weapons represent an unprecedented threat
造成前所未有的威胁
to countless millions.
你的任务  若你选择接受
Your mission, should you choose to accept it,
就是阻止使徒拿到钚核
is to prevent the Apostles from acquiring plutonium
使徒
不择一切手段
using any means at your disposal.
如果你或任何你的IMF组员被捕或被杀
If you or any members of your IMF team are caught or killed,
部长都会否认对你们的行动知情
the Secretary will disavow any knowledge of your actions.
祝你好运  伊森
Good luck, Ethan.
本条信息将在五秒后自毁
This message will self-destruct in five seconds.
柏林
他迟到了
He's late.
-他从来不迟到的  -他会来的
- He's never late. - He'll be here.
我感觉很不好
I don't like it.
这家伙身上有什么东西让我不安
Something about this guy just really gives me the creeps.
好了  放松
Okay, just relax.
我很放松
I'm relaxed.
你听起来不像是放松的样子
You don't sound relaxed.
路德  他听起来放松吗
Luther, does he sound relaxed to you?
他听起来害怕极了
He sounds terrified.
拜托  我没有害怕
Please, I'm not terrified.
我只是有种不祥的预感
I just have a bad feeling is all.
你刚刚不是说你很放松吗
I thought you said you were relaxed.
放松的同时又极度不安
It's entirely possible to be relaxed and extremely uneasy
是完全有可能的
at the same time.
-不  不可能  -你就总这样
- No, it's not. - You do it all the time.
-不  我没有  -你就是
- No, I don't. - Yes, you do.
不  他没有
No, he doesn't.
你想让我相信你现在完全放松
I'm supposed to believe that you are perfectly relaxed,
-此时此地...  -班吉
- right here, now... - Benji.
在一条黑暗的小巷里  等着从一个变态手中
...in a dark alleyway, waiting to buy black-market plutonium
买黑市钚核
from a psychopath.
班吉  我不会让你出事的
Benji, I won't let anything happen to you.
-好把  -瞧吧  班吉 你非常安全
- Okay. - See, Benji, you're perfectly safe.
你说得轻松  你可是坐在车里
That's easy for you to say, you're in the van.
是你想出外勤的  "硬汉"
Well, you wanted to be in the field, tough guy.
但今晚  路德  我想待在车里
And tonight, Luther, I would like to be in the van!
他来了
He's here.
天呐
Oh, God.
准备好钱  路德
Have that money ready, Luther.
收到
Copy.
伊森  你能收到吗
Ethan, do you copy?
你能收到吗
Do you copy?
我们到底还做不做交易了
Are we finally gonna do this or not?
我能在这行生存下来
I have survived in this business
全靠我脑海中的一个声音
with the help of a voice in my head.
这个声音从来不出错  而无论我何时遇到你
This voice is never wrong. And whenever I meet you,
它总会跟我说同一句话
it tells me the same thing.
什么
What's that?
什么都没有
Nothing.
我是来做生意的  让你的声音扔硬币决定吧
I'm here to do business. Tell the voice to flip a coin.
那是什么
What's that?
这是根铍棒
This is a beryllium rod,
它引发里面的钚产生了反应
which is causing a reaction with the plutonium inside the core.
没问题
That's them.
钱呢
The money?
钱
The money.
把钱拿过来
Bring the money.
路德  把钱拿过来
Luther, bring the money.
我们需要那笔钱  路德
We're gonna need that money, Luther.
杀了他们
Kill them.
我来拿
I got it!
路德  你能收到吗
Luther, do you copy?
路德
Luther!
路德  快回话
Luther, come in.
路德现在不在
Luther's not here right now.
使徒能为你做什么  亨特
What can the Apostles do for you, Hunt?
-你们想要什么  -你们被包围了  亨特
- What do you want? - You're boxed in, Hunt.
把钚给我们  然后离开
Give us the plutonium and walk away.
班吉  把车开来
Benji, get the car.
我可能做不到
I don't think I can do that.
班吉  把车开来
Benji, get the car.
我们跟你做个交易  亨特
We'll make you a deal, Hunt.
把钚给我们  我们就不杀你的朋友
Give us the plutonium and we won't kill your friend.
别  伊森  别为了我这么做
Don't you do it, Ethan! Not for me!
我数到三
I'm gonna count to three.
一
One.
-二  -路德
- Two. - Luther...
-对不起  -三
- I'm sorry. - Three.
对不起  我不知道还能怎么办
I'm sorry. I didn't know what else to do.
我不会放在心上的
We're good.
-你还好吗  -我本该已经死了
- You okay? - I should be dead.
我们都该已经死了
We should all be dead.
为什么我们没有死
Why aren't we?
钚核呢
Where's the plutonium?
不在了
It's gone.
如果您刚刚打开电视
If you're just joining us,
三起大爆炸事件同时发生
three massive explosions have gone off simultaneously
突发新闻  三起核武器袭击
目前看来是联合恐怖袭击
in what appears to be a coordinated attack.
这是从罗马拍摄到的梵蒂冈的实时画面
This image is live in Rome, looking toward the Vatican
而这是我们的镜头能到达的最近距离了
and is as close as our cameras can get.
据消息称  爆炸发生时
It is believed that the Pope was in residence
教皇正位于他的居所内
at the time of the blast.
这是从耶路撒冷城外拍摄到的城内的实时画面
Also live, we're looking at Jerusalem from just outside the city.
接下来是圣城麦加的实时画面
Also live, the holy city of Mecca
是停靠在沙特阿拉伯附近的红海上的
from the USS Ronald Reagan in the Red Sea
里根号航空母舰拍摄到的
off the coast of Saudi Arabia.
已经探测到了核辐射
Radiation has been detected,
意味着这些令人震惊的袭击
indicating that nuclear weapons were used
使用了核武器
in these unspeakable attacks.
-伊森  时间到了  -目前虽没有具体伤亡数字
- Ethan, it's time. - No word on casualties yet,
但我们可以预计
but we can assume
死亡人数将是灾难级的
the death toll is catastrophic.
初期报告显示  制造袭击中使用的武器
Early reports suggest the weapons used
需要极其专业的知识
would require highly specialized knowledge
而只有极少数人具备这样的知识
that very few people possess.
现在的问题是  谁会同时袭击这三座宗教圣城
The question now is who would attack all three of these holy sites?
以及为什么
And why?
三起袭击精确地发生在同一时刻
The attacks occurred at precisely the same moment,
就在一个多小时前
just over an hour ago,
东部时间凌晨4点
at 4:00 a.m. Eastern Time.
爆炸发生几分钟内
Within minutes of the attack,
国会紧急休会
Congress ordered an emergency recess
国会大厦被疏散
and the Capitol Building was evacuated.
总统乘坐空军一号离开了华盛顿
The President left Washington on Air Force One.
白宫宣布进入紧急状态
The White House has declared a state of emergency,
命令军队处于最高戒备
placing the military on highest alert.
能让我们单独待会儿吗  谢谢
Would you excuse us, please?
德布朗克博士
Dr. Delbruuk.
我们知道你是谁
We know who you are.
我们看了宣言  也找到了你的实验室
We read the manifesto, we found your lab.
机密
"所有的和平
"There has never been peace
都需要伟大的牺牲
"without first a great suffering.
牺牲越大  和平越久"
"The greater the suffering, the greater the peace."
这能让他们团结起来  知道吗
See, this will unite them. Hmm?
他们读到这份宣言的时候就会懂的
When they read this manifesto, they'll all understand.
永远都不会有人读到这份宣言
Nobody's gonna read that manifesto, ever.
我可以向你保证
I can promise you that.
今天是几号
What day is it?
我在这儿多久了
How long have I been here?
你记得的最后一件事是什么
What's the last thing you remember?
我在开车
I was driving.
有人撞了我
Someone hit me.
那是两周前了
That was two weeks ago.
-两周  -两周
- Two weeks? - Two weeks.
这是你的  是不是
This is yours, isn't it?
拉克就是用这个跟你联系的
It's how Lark communicated with you.
-拉克  -约翰·拉克
- Lark? - John Lark.
-我们知道关于他的一切  -你们什么都不知道
- We know all about him. - You know nothing.
这手机上有线索能帮我们找到他
There's information in this phone that could lead us to him.
而你知道密码
And you have the passcode.
你们觉得拉克是敌人  是吗
You think Lark is the enemy, hmm?
但你们
But you,
无论你们是谁  你们才是敌人
well, whoever you are, you are the enemy.
你们才是这个体制得以苟存的原因
You're why the system survives.
-劫难不断持续的原因  -闭嘴
- Why the suffering goes on. - Shut up!
我们不在乎你  我们只想抓到拉克
We don't care about you. We want Lark.
我们做个交易如何
What if we make a deal?
不  没有交易  路德
No, there's no deal, Luther.
出去一下
Step outside.
让我和这家伙待五分钟
Give me five minutes with this guy.
伊森  我不能让你这么做  我们不是这样的人
Ethan, I can't let you do that. That's not who we are.
或许我们该重新考虑这一点了
Then maybe we need to reconsider that.
如果他们在电视上宣读这份宣言呢
What if they read the manifesto on the air?
什么  你能做到这个
What? You can do that?
我们打个电话就能做到
We can do it with a phone call.
如果他宣读了拉克的宣言...
Well, if he reads Lark's manifesto...
不行
No.
我就把密码给你
I'll give you the passcode.
伊森  伊森
Ethan! Ethan!
想想  伊森
Think, Ethan.
为了大局着想  拜托
Think of the greater good, please.
没错  只要你们这么做就行
Yeah, you do that.
长官
Sir.
不  他不愿意合作
No, he won't cooperate.
是的  长官  除非我们宣读那份宣言
Yes, sir. If we read the manifesto
在直播中读
on the air.
我很抱歉  长官
I'm sorry, sir.
贸易以及全球市场大幅下跌
Trading and global markets plummeted.
等等  我刚收到消息
Stand by. I'm told
我们有一些额外的消息要报道
we're about to get some additional information.
我刚刚拿到了一份来自尼尔斯·德布朗克的文件
I've just been handed a document from Nils Delbruuk,
他是一位核武器专家
a nuclear weapons specialist
并声称自己是袭击中所使用的武器的制造者
who claims to have built the weapons used in these attacks.
我被要求完整朗读这份宣言
I've been asked to read this manifesto in its entirety.
"所有的和平  都需要伟大的牺牲
"There has never been peace without first a great suffering."
牺牲越大  和平越久
"The greater the suffering, the greater the peace."
人类正在走上自毁之途
"As mankind is drawn to his self-destruction"
犹如飞蛾扑火般
"like a moth to the candle,"
那些所谓的和平捍卫者
"the so-called defenders of peace,"
教会  政府  法律
"the church, the government, the law,"
孜孜不倦地阻止人类自毁"
"work tirelessly to save humanity from itself."
现在你们要这些也没用了
It's not gonna help you now.
"但为了避免灾难
"But by averting disaster,"
他们选择推迟..."
"they serve to delay a peace..."
木已成舟
What's done is done.
"只有经过火的洗礼才能最终诞生的和平
"...that can only come through an inevitable baptism of fire."
我带给你们的灾难不是末日的开始
"The suffering I bring you is not the beginning of the end."
而是一个更好的  互相理解的世界的开始"
"It is the beginning of a greater mutual understanding..."
拿到了吗
Did we get it?
"这是迈向人类终极团结的第一步"
"It is the first step toward the ultimate brotherhood of man."
拿到了
We got it.
"我带给你们的灾难
"The suffering I bring you"
是通往终极和平的桥梁"
"is the bridge to ultimate peace."
撤
Go.
拿到了吗
Did we get it?
当然拿到了
Of course we got it.
我就说我们会拿到的
I told you we'd get it.
我不明白
I don't understand.
袭击还没发生吗
The attacks didn't happen?
你是在一小时之前出的车祸
The car accident you were in, that was an hour ago.
撞你的那辆车就是我开的
I was driving the other car.
木是不是已经成了舟
What's done is done,
那得我们说了算
when we say it's done.
碟中谍6: 全面瓦解
德国  拉姆施泰因空军基地
长官
Sir.
你解锁的那个手机让我们找到了一个冰岛的服务器
That phone you unlocked led us to a server in Iceland
我们成功解码了一份
where we managed to decrypt a communique
约翰·拉克和这个女人之间的公报
between John Lark and this woman:
阿拉娜·米索普利斯  活动家以及慈善家
Alana Mitsopolis, activist and philanthropist,
她进行的慈善活动
whose charity work
让她得到了白寡妇的绰号
has earned her the nickname the White Widow.
这些都是为了掩护她真正的交易
It's all a front for her real trade:
武器贸易  洗钱
arms dealing, money laundering.
广泛的政府关系也为她提供了保护
Extensive political connections provide her with protection.
拉克和寡妇今晚要碰面
Lark and the Widow are meeting tonight
来协商关于某个未知包裹的交付问题
to negotiate delivery of an unspecified package,
我们只能假设这个包裹是我们丢失的钚核
which we can only assume is our missing plutonium.
他们会在巴黎大皇宫的私人会所碰头
They'll make contact in a private lounge at the Grand Palais in Paris
她会在那里举办她的年度筹款活动
during her annual fundraising event.
细节全在文件里
The details are in the file.
如果拉克在午夜12点还没有出现
If Lark isn't there by midnight,
白寡妇就会离开
the Widow will leave
并且把包裹出售给出价最高者
and sell the package to the highest bidder.
你还剩两小时来找到拉克
Which gives you two hours from now to find Lark.
长官  我想有些事情你需要知道
Sir, I think there's something you need to know.
-我...  -我必须马上打断你
- I... - I'm gonna stop you right there
你在柏林时面临的是艰难的选择
You had a terrible choice to make in Berlin:
是保住钚核还是去救你的队员
Recover the plutonium or save your team.
你选择了队员  现在整个世界都陷入了危机
You chose your team, and now the world is at risk.
你自身本质的某些缺陷
Some flaw deep in your core being
让你无法在一条命和数百万条生命之间抉择
simply won't allow you to choose between one life and millions.
你认为这是你的弱点
You see that as a sign of weakness.
但对我而言  这正是你最强大的力量
To me, that's your greatest strength.
这也说明有朝一日我可以指望你来救我的命
It also tells me I can count on you to cover my ass.
因为虽然从中情局调来这里是平级调动
Because coming over here from the CIA was a lateral move,
也有人说是降职了
some say a step down.
但我还是到这里来了
But I did it
因为你
because of you.
别让我后悔
Don't make me regret it.
打电话
Make the call.
把飞机停下
Shut 'em down.
你以为你在干什么  艾瑞卡
What do you think you're doing, Erika?
这个任务可能是你的
It may be your mission,
但这架飞机是中情局的
but this is the CIA's plane.
没我的允许  它就不能起飞
It doesn't take off without my say-so.
我没时间跟你争
We don't have time for this.
我在巴黎的小队已经准备好了
I have a team in Paris ready to grab Lark
拉克一离开大楼我们就会抓住他
as soon as he leaves the building.
一架G5飞机会把他引渡到关塔那摩监狱
A G5 standing by to rendition him to Gitmo,
我们会在那里拷问他
where a waterboard is waiting.
花上无谓的24小时来问出一份我们无法相信的口供
Spend 24 hours we don't have to pull a confession we can't trust
供述者还连身份都不能确定  我不认同这方案
from a man we haven't positively identified? No.
我们需要可靠的情报  现在就要
We need reliable intelligence, and we need it now.
IMF的存在就是为了处理这种情况
This scenario is precisely why the IMF exists!
IMF就是万圣节闹剧  艾伦
The IMF is Halloween, Alan.
一群成年人戴着面具在玩不给糖就捣蛋
A bunch of grown men in rubber masks playing trick-or-treat.
如果他在柏林时能保住钚核
And if he had held on to the plutonium in Berlin,
我们也不用在这里争了
we wouldn't be having this conversation.
但那样他的队员就会死
And his team would be dead.
确实  他们会死
Yes. They would.
那就是职责所在
That's the job.
正因此我才希望现场有一个我的人
And that's why I want one of my own men on the scene
来评估情况
to appraise the situation.
沃克特工  来自特别行动组
Agent Walker, Special Activities.
他的名声我早有耳闻
His reputation precedes.
你习惯用手术刀
You use a scalpel.
我更喜欢用锤子
I prefer a hammer.
我不同意
The answer is no.
我有直接来自总统的行动授权
I have operational authority here, direct from the President.
你要是有异议  就自己去找他
You have a problem with that, you take it up with him.
我已经找过了  他也同意了
I have already, and he agrees with me.
要么我的人跟着去  要么谁都别想去
My man goes or no one goes.
绝不能让任何人阻止你拿到钚核
No one comes between you and that plutonium.
亨特不能  他的队员不能  任何人都不能
Not Hunt, not his team, not anyone.
白寡妇在政府各层都有眼线
The White Widow has spies at every level of government.
这架飞机伪装成了商用客机
This plane is posing as a commercial airliner
这样我们就能跳伞进入法国境内而不被发现
so we can jump into France undetected.
她和拉克会于午夜12点在贵宾厅见面
The Widow's meeting Lark in the VIP lounge at midnight.
没有预先发放的电子手环  任何人都不能进去
No one will be admitted without a pre-issued electronic I.D. band.
我们已经拿到了拉克手环上的射频识别码
We have acquired the unique RFID number for Lark's band,
这样我们就可以定位他
allowing us to locate it
用这些
with these.
找到那个手环  就找到了拉克
Find that I.D. band, you find Lark.
然后呢
Then what?
然后...
Then...
我借用他的身份来与白寡妇联系
I assume his identity and make contact with the Widow.
让她领着我们找到包裹
She takes us to the package.
真的有人信你这烂招吗
People actually fall for this shit?
你准备怎么让拉克合作
How do you intend to make Lark cooperate?
我在人群中撞他一下
I bump him in the crowd.
不出十秒  他就会跟派对上的其他醉汉一样
In ten seconds he'll look like any other drunk at the party,
语无伦次  毫无还手之力
incoherent and completely pliable.
我装成他的样子之后
After I borrow his face,
你就带他走出前门
you walk him out the front door
把他交给斯隆的撤离小队
and hand him to Sloane's extraction team.
你可别想这么轻易就甩掉我  亨特
You're not getting rid of me that easily, Hunt.
我这么做不是为了甩掉你
That's not what this is about.
当然就是
Sure it is.
我知道你不想让我插手这次的行动
I know you don't want me on this detail.
但我们还是面对现实吧
But let's face it:
如果你在柏林能狠一狠心
If you'd made the hard choice in Berlin,
我就不会在这里了
I wouldn't be here.
如果你没有击毙
And if you hadn't gunned down
他们派你去追查的每一个辛迪加特工
every Syndicate agent they sent you to find,
我也不用出现在这里了
I wouldn't be here.
没错  我知道关于你的一切
That's right, I know all about you.
就是因为你  我们才没有活着的证人
You're why we don't have a living witness
能来指认约翰·拉克或者使徒
who can identify John Lark or the Apostles.
如果你对我的方法有意见
If you have a problem with my methods,
你可以一直留在后方
you can always stay behind.
"你的任务  由你来决定是否接受"
"Your mission, should you choose to accept it."
是这么说的吧
Isn't that the thing?
两分钟之后开始减压
Two minutes to decompression.
穿上装备  白寡妇半小时后就要跟拉克会面了
Suit up. The Widow is meeting Lark in 30 minutes.
十秒钟之后开始减压
Ten seconds to decompression.
你的氧气开了吗
Is your oxygen on?
这个海拔高度大气稀薄
There is no atmosphere at this altitude.
我可不希望你晕过去
I don't need you blacking out on me.
你头盔上的屏幕有内置的导航系统
Your heads-up display has a built-in guidance system.
跟着它降落到目的地
Follow it to the target.
系统告诉你开伞时你再开
Open your chute when the system says,
不许早也不许晚
not before and definitely not after,
否则最后经过你大脑的
or the last thing that goes through your mind
就是你的膝盖骨  明白了吗
will be your kneecaps. Is that clear?
明白
Crystal.
我们需要谈谈  需要重新制定计划
We got to talk. We need to rethink this.
别挡路  亨特
Out of my way, Hunt.
沃克  现在有问题
Walker, we've got a problem.
外面风暴肆虐  我们需要...
There's a storm. We need to...
别说了
Enough talk.
巴黎见
I'll see you in Paris.
拜托  拜托  拜托
Come on, come on, come on.
海拔  25000英尺
Altitude: 25,000 feet.
沃克
Walker?
怎么了  亨特  这点闪电就让你怕了吗
What's the matter, Hunt? You afraid of a little lightning?
海拔  20000英尺
Altitude: 20,000 feet.
该死的
Son of a bitch.
沃克
Walker?
你听得到吗
Do you copy?
沃克
Walker?
Walker.
拜托
Come on.
海拔  15000英尺
Altitude: 15,000 feet.
沃克
Walker.
Walker!
沃克
海拔  10000英尺
Altitude: 10,000 feet.
9000英尺
9,000.
见鬼
Oh, shit.
8000英尺
8,000.
7000英尺
7,000.
6000英尺
6,000.
5000英尺
5,000.
4000英尺
4,000.
沃克
Walker!
3000英尺
3,000.
开伞  开伞  开伞
Deploy. Deploy. Deploy.
开伞  开伞
Deploy. Deploy.
天呐
Oh, God.
看来你氧气断了啊
Looks like you lost your oxygen.
白寡妇和拉克就在那里碰头
That's where the Widow is meeting Lark.
伊森
Ethan.
-沃克  -伊森  如果你能听见我说话
- Walker. - Ethan, if you can hear me,
我找到他了
I've got him.
再说一遍  哪里
Say again. Where?
他朝洗手间去了
He's headed for the bathroom.
-针剂在哪  -不需要了
- Where's the needle? - Didn't need it.
把他抬起来
Get him up.
别害羞嘛  人多更好玩
开门嘛  我们没有恶意的
-我们能加入你们吗  -我们不会咬人的
该死
Shit.
-你还能做面具吗  -我至少得有张脸啊
- Can you still make a mask? - I need a face to make a mask.
抱歉  我本来瞄准的是他的胸口
Sorry. I was aiming for his chest.
-你在这里干什么  -我也很高兴再见到你
- What are you doing here? - It's good to see you, too.
抱歉  我糊涂了  你是...
I'm sorry, I'm confused. You are...
一位老朋友
An old friend.
取消撤离小队  目标已死亡
Cancel extraction. We're code blue.
派清理人员来
Send sanitation.
北侧男洗手间
North men's room.
你没有回答我的问题  你在这里干什么
You didn't answer my question. What are you doing here?
就这样  放轻松  就是这样
That's it. Just take it easy. That's it.
保持抬头的姿势直到停止出血为止
Just keep your head back until the bleeding stops.
有问题吗
What is it? Eh?
你们也想试试吗
你在这里不是巧合  谁派你来的
You're not here by accident. Who sent you?
我不能告诉你
I can't tell you that.
你要干什么
What are you doing?
我和那个白寡妇有个约会
I have a date with the White Widow.
是他和那个寡妇有个约会  而你长得一点也不像他
He had a date with the Widow. You look nothing like him.
现在我们只能希望他们从未见过面了
And now we have to hope they never met.
-希望可不是什么策略  -你一定是新来的
- Hope is not a strategy! - Oh, you must be new.
我别无选择
I have no other choice.
白寡妇是我们唯一的线索
The White Widow's our only lead.
我必须假扮成这家伙5分钟
I got to be this guy for five minutes.
-不要这么做  -什么
- Don't do it. - What?
到底怎么了  你向我隐瞒了什么
What is it? What aren't you telling me?
你并不清楚你被卷入了什么麻烦
You don't understand what you're involved in.
我不清楚我被卷入了什么
I don't understand what I'm involved in.
I don't understand what I'm involved in?
我到底被卷入了什么
What am I involved in?
如果你要和寡妇见面  她3分钟后就走了
If you're meeting the Widow, she leaves in three minutes.
-伊森  -我会搞定的
- Ethan! - I'll make it work.
我叫沃克
The name's Walker.
是吗  不用谢
Yeah? You're welcome.
你以为你在干什么
What do you think you're doing?
-我和你一起去  -不行
- I'm going with you. - Like hell you are.
有一些人被派来杀拉克
People have been sent here to kill Lark.
可不是嘛
No shit.
不  不是我  是那些合约杀手和雇佣杀手
No, not me. Contractors. Paid assassins.
他们不知道他长什么样
They don't know what he looks like,
他们只知道他半夜要和寡妇见面
they only know he's meeting the Widow at midnight.
如果你这么做
If you go through with this,
他们会认为你就是拉克
they're gonna believe you're Lark
然后杀了你
and they're gonna kill you.
你怎么知道这些的
How do you know all this?
我不能告诉你
I can't tell you that.
你应该彻底金盆洗手的
You should've stayed out of the game.
你当初应该跟我一起走的
You should've come with me.
这场慈善晚会是为了纪念我的母亲而举办的
This charity was started in honor of my mother.
你们中认识她的人都了解她的力量
Those of you who knew her understood her strength,
她的坚韧  她的足智多谋
her tenacity, her resourcefulness.
但她还有着另外一面
But there was another side to her,
大多数人从未见过的一面
a side most people never saw.
正是她精神中的那一部分
It is that part of her spirit that has brought us
让我们今晚齐聚一堂
all together tonight.
麦克丝有点自相矛盾
Max was something of a paradox.
她对矛盾非常着迷
She had a fascination for paradoxes,
而这种情感传承到了我身上
a fascination she passed on to me.
麦克丝看透了我们现在生活的这个世界
Max had no illusions about the world we live in today.
但她梦想着能有一个截然不同的未来
But she had dreams of a very different future.
一个不再需要她独特才能的世界
One in which her unique talents were no longer required.
她从这个世界的方式中所获得的一切
All she earned from the way the world is
最终都是为了让它成为将来可能成为的样子
went ultimately to making it what it could someday be.
那样的未来还没有到来
That future isn't here yet.
而今晚  你们的慷慨捐赠
Tonight, your contributions
让我们离那个世界更近了一步
have brought it just a little closer.
感谢大家的光临
Thank you all for coming.
请享受这场盛宴
Enjoy the party.
你不可能是约翰·拉克
You can't possibly be John Lark.
实际上  我并不是
I'm not, actually.
那只是个化名
It's an alias.
或许它至少比无名氏要好
I suppose it's better than John Doe.
你还有什么别的名字吗
Is there another name you prefer?
有什么地方我们可以私下谈谈吗
Is there somewhere we could talk privately?
我其实挺喜欢「拉克」这名字  有种独特的魅力
In fact I like "Lark." It does have a certain ring.
我们没有多少时间
We don't have a lot of time.
因为说实话
'Cause I'll be honest with you.
从你在外的名声来看  我没想到你会这么帅
A man of your reputation, I was expecting someone uglier.
不要被外表所欺  我的真面目也很凶恶丑陋
Don't let looks deceive. I'm as ugly as they come.
我也说句实话  你的生命处于危险之中
And I'll be honest with you. Your life is in danger.
不准碰她
Don't you touch her.
放轻松  这是我哥哥
Relax. It's my brother.
你对我们的客人很粗鲁  佐拉
You're being rude to our guest, Zola.
该走了
It's time to go.
别在这儿闹得很难看
Don't turn this into a scene.
你不会想和这个人待在一起的
You don't want to be with this one.
-你刚说什么来着  -你的生命处于危险之中
- You were saying? - Your life is in danger.
谁会想杀了我
And who would want to kill me?
首先  美国人
The Americans, for starters.
如果真是这样  那我早就知道了
If that were true, I would know it.
你认为你是唯一一个
You think you're the only one
在政府内部有间谍的人吗
with spies in the government?
这里有人不希望我跟你见面
There are people here who don't want this meeting to happen.
不相信我吗
Don't believe me?
看看周围
Look around.
我知道你在想什么
I know what you're thinking.
也许他们不是来杀你的
Maybe they're not here for you.
也许他们的目标是我
Maybe they're just here for me.
你愿意冒这个险吗
Are you willing to take that chance?
你有我想要的东西
You have something I want.
而这让我成为你唯一可以信任
Right now, that makes me the only person you can trust
让你活着离开这里的人
to get you out of here alive.
还是说你更愿意依靠你哥哥
Or would you rather leave that to your brother?
我想马上回家  拉克先生
I think I'd like to go home now, Mr. Lark.
法国政府今天中午已经收到了「货」
The French government took receipt of the asset at noon today.
并将在明天早上8点
Delivery will be via air to the Finance Ministry
空运至财政部
at 8:00 a.m. tomorrow morning.
一支在警方严密护送下的装甲车队
An armored motorcade under heavy police escort
将通过这条路线运送他
will transport him via this route.
我们将在这个十字路口制造障碍
We'll create a diversion at this intersection, here.
车队将会自动行驶
The motorcade will automatically take
到这条预选的备用路线
the preplanned alternate route here,
我们到时候半路截取「货物」
where we'll extract the asset.
截取「货物」
Extract the asset?
这就是「货物」
The asset.
我们为了这条消息花了很大一笔钱
We paid a great deal of money for this information.
他们什么都交代清楚了  除了这个人的名字
They gave us everything but this man's name.
你不会碰巧知道他是谁  对吧
You don't happen to know who he is, do you?
他的名字叫所罗门·莱恩
His name is Solomon Lane.
本来是英国特工  叛变成了无政府主义者
British Special Agent turned anarchist.
他利用变节特工
He used rogue covert operatives
创建了一个被称为辛迪加的恐怖网络
to create a terror network called the Syndicate.
到处搞破坏  暗杀  大屠杀
Sabotage, assassination, mass murder.
极度凶恶丑陋
As ugly as they come.
两年前他曾被美国特工抓捕
He was captured by American agents two years ago.
从那以后  他一直在被无休止地审讯
Since then, he's been in a never-ending interrogation,
从一个政府转到另一个政府手上
passed around from one government to another
为他的罪行负责
to answer for his crimes.
你看上去不太高兴  拉克
You seem displeased, Lark.
也许我没有表达清楚
Perhaps I didn't make myself clear.
我来巴黎是为了钚核
I came to Paris for plutonium.
这其中一定有些误会
Well, there must be a misunderstanding.
我只是个中间人
I'm just a broker.
我负责联系买主和卖主
I connect a buyer and a seller.
我的卖家对现金不感兴趣
My seller's not interested in cash,
所以如果你想要钚核
so if you want the plutonium...
就必须截获莱恩
Extract Lane
然后进行交易
and make a trade.
没错
That's right.
我怎么知道卖家有我想要的东西
How do I know the seller has what I want?
这是充满诚意的定金
A down payment in good faith.
信使会在48小时内送来另外两枚
A courier will deliver two more within 48 hours
来交换他
in exchange for him.
好吧
All right.
改道后会发生什么
What happens after the diversion?
把所有人都杀了
Kill everyone?
这就是你的计划吗
That's your plan?
不会有目击者
There will be no witnesses.
我如何保证莱恩能在行动中活下来
What's my guarantee that lane walks out of this thing alive?
他在一个装甲箱里
He's in an armored box.
等到安全时  我们才会把他放出来
We'll pull him out when it's safe.
你想要拿到钚核
You want your plutonium,
这就是代价
this is the price.
还是说你的底线是不能杀警察
Or do you draw the line at killing cops?
这位可是约翰·拉克啊
That's John Lark you're talking to.
我用天花谋杀妇女和儿童
I murder women and children with smallpox.
我没有底线
I have no line.
很好
Right.
大家好好休息吧  明天会很忙
Sleep well, everyone. Busy day tomorrow.
你一定是在跟我开玩笑
You have got to be kidding me.
如果你想让莱恩从监狱里出来  就只能这么做
If you want Lane out of prison, this is how it gets done.
我想让拉克把他救出来  不是伊森·亨特
I wanted Lark to break him out, not Ethan Hunt.
我想要拉克去交易  不是伊森·亨特
I wanted Lark at the exchange, not Ethan Hunt.
我想要拉克引我们找到钚核
I wanted Lark to lead us to the plutonium
和使徒
and the Apostles.
你或许仍然有机会
You may still get your chance.
你忘了我们从巴黎大皇宫
Have you forgotten about the corpse we pulled
男厕所拖出来的那具尸体吗
out of the men's room at the Grand Palais?
我猜那并不是拉克
I'm guessing that wasn't Lark.
更有可能是拉克的手下
More likely one of Lark's recruits.
根据我们的情报显示并不是
Not according to our intelligence.
情报是由谁收集的
Intelligence gathered by whom?
亨特
Hunt.
你一直怀疑拉克是一名美国特工
You've long held suspicions that Lark was an American agent.
了解我们一举一动的人
Someone who knew our every move.
能像幽灵一样来去无踪的人
Someone who could come and go like a ghost.
你的意思是说亨特就是约翰·拉克
You're suggesting Hunt is John Lark.
你为了自保不惜抓住任何救命稻草  沃克
You're reaching, Walker. Trying to save your ass.
这可行不通
It won't work.
你仔细想想  一个像拉克那么小心的人
Think about it. Would a man as careful as Lark
真的会冒这样的风险吗
really stick his neck out like that?
就为了和白寡妇面对面交易
For a face-to-face with the White Widow?
-他会派代理人去  -一个诱饵
- He'd send a proxy. - A decoy.
如果他真的足够聪明
And if he was really smart,
他会让他的女性朋友
he'd have his lady friend
在可靠的证人  也就是我的面前  杀死那个诱饵
kill that decoy in front of a reliable witness. Me.
拉网式搜捕即将围剿他的恐怖主义第二人格
The dragnet is closing in on his terrorist alter ego.
所以他花钱请一个人来扮演拉克的角色
So he pays a man to play the part of Lark
然后杀死他
and has him killed.
在为国家服务的幌子下
And under the guise of serving his country...
伪装出他自己的秘密身份
Assumes his own secret identity.
在美国政府的全力支持下  可以恣意妄为
Free to operate at will with the full support of the U.S. government.
为什么
Why?
亨特为什么要背叛
Why would Hunt turn?
莱恩为什么背叛  他的使徒又为什么这么做
Why did Lane do it? Why did any of his Apostles?
他们都曾有着崇高的信仰
They were believers in a cause.
当那个信仰被证实是谎言的时候
And when that cause turned out to be a lie,
他们就背叛了自己的主人
they turned against their masters.
亨特的政府背叛了他多少次
How many times has Hunt's government betrayed him,
否认他的存在  把他丢到一边
disavowed him, cast him aside?
像他这样的人  忍到什么时候就忍无可忍了呢
And how long before a man like that has had enough?
这是一个严重的指控
That is a serious accusation.
你能证实吗
Can you prove it?
这是我们在巴黎大皇宫
This is the phone we pulled off the dead body
从尸体身上找到的手机
at the Grand Palais.
我猜里面会有你需要的所有证据
I'm guessing it has all the proof you need.
莱恩真的曾用毒气毒死了一个有两千人的村庄吗
Is it true Lane gassed a village of 2,000 people?
是的
Yes.
他真的曾击落一架客机
Is it true he brought down an entire passenger plane
就为了杀死一个人吗
just to kill one man?
是的
Yes.
-他真的...  -沃克
- Is it true that he... - Hey, Walker.
不管你听说了什么  只要让你觉得毛骨悚然
Whatever you heard, if it makes your skin crawl,
那很可能就是真的了
it's probably true.
天呐
Holy shit.
你就是抓住他的那个人  对吗
You're the guy that caught him, aren't you?
你觉得他能把这件事隐瞒多久
How long do you think he's gonna keep that to himself?
到时候见机行事  阻止他说出来
We'll burn that bridge when we get to it.
他在搞什么鬼
What the hell is he doing?
亨特  你在哪儿
Hunt? Where are you?
别等我了
Don't wait for me!
怎么了  出什么事了
What is it? What's wrong?
我们在车库见面
I'll meet you at the garage.
班吉  你收到了吗
Benji, do you copy?
我们收到  说
We copy. Go.
改变计划  我暴露了  需要协助脱身
Change of plan. I'm blown. Need extraction.
我们马上赶来
We're on our way.
他正从巴黎圣母院前往圣路易斯大桥
各小队正在追捕
停下
站在原地
上车
Get in the car.
都不许动
举起手来
赶快离开  拜托了
所有人  都举起手来
离开这里  拜托了
佐拉想跟你谈谈
Zola wants a word with you.
要怎么处理她
了结掉她
你不会有事的
我们该走了
We got to go.
我很抱歉
快点
Come on.
顺便说下  我叫沃克
The name's Walker, by the way.
是你选的这么小的车吗
Was the little car your idea?
天呐
Jesus Christ!
怎么回事
What the hell was that?
-都下车  -快快快
- Everybody out. - Go, go, go!
那是伊尔莎
That was Ilsa.
闭嘴
Shut up.
真有意思
Very interesting.
很高兴再次见到你  伊森
It's good to see you again, Ethan.
瞧瞧谁还活着呢
Oh, look who's still alive.
他的脖子里有个微波追踪器
There's a microwave tracker in his neck.
明白了  你知道该怎么做
Got it. You know what to do.
我向你保证  一点都不疼...才怪
Let me just assure you, this won't hurt...enough.
我们有90秒的时间
Ninety seconds.
你和你的使徒以为
You and your Apostles think
我们会用你来换丢失的钚核
we're gonna trade you for the missing plutonium.
我来告诉你那是不可能的
I'm here to tell you that's never gonna happen.
"你的任务  请选择是否接受"
"Your mission, should you choose to accept it."
我想知道  伊森
I wonder, Ethan,
你选择过不接受吗
did you ever choose not to?
你有停下来问过自己
Did you ever stop and ask yourself
给你下命令的人是谁或者背后的原因吗
who it was giving you the orders or why?
每一天  你侍奉的主人
While every day the master you serve
距离让世界毁灭都更近了一步
moves one step closer to ending the world.
恐怖分子做出这样的指控还真奇怪
Strange accusation coming from a terrorist.
60秒
Sixty seconds.
恐怖分子就像是渴求被关注的学生
Terrorists are schoolboys desperate for attention,
寄希望于用恐惧来改变公众的观念
hoping to shape public opinion through fear.
我才不关心人们会怎么想或是什么感受
I don't care in the least what people think or feel.
根据我的经验  他们很快就会忘了
In my experience, they don't do either for very long.
那就能成为你炸毁工厂
Oh, and I suppose that justifies bombing factories
炸掉民用飞机的合理理由吗
or bringing down civilian aircraft.
或者给我绑上炸弹背心
Or strapping me into an explosive vest!
最后一项还没完成  有趣的小朋友
Consider it unfinished business, my funny little friend.
-路德  -快了
- Luther? - Almost there.
你和我一样看得清结局  伊森
You see the end as clearly as I do, Ethan.
全世界的政府都陷入了疯狂
Governments the world over are descending into madness.
建立辛迪加的目的就是一点一点地摧毁他们
The Syndicate was created to tear them down, brick by brick.
辛迪加是一群只知道杀人的懦夫
The Syndicate was a pack of murdering cowards.
辛迪加是文明最后的希望
The Syndicate was civilization's last hope!
一个粉碎旧的世界秩序的机会
A chance to smash the old world order.
那个希望现在破灭了
That hope is gone now
就因为你和你可悲的道德观
because of you and your pathetic morality.
你应该杀了我的  伊森
You should have killed me, Ethan.
你一直害怕的结局
The end you've always feared
就要来了
is coming.
It's coming!
你的双手将沾满鲜血
And the blood will be on your hands.
都是你的好意造成的彻底毁灭
The fallout of all your good intentions.
-时间到了  -取出来了
- Time. - Got it.
拉他起来
Get him up.
现在你是我的了
You're mine now.
你身上真是充满惊喜  拉克
You're just full of surprises, Lark.
你哥哥的计划从一开始就注定失败
Your brother's plan was bad from the word go.
你会丧失所有手下
You'd have lost all your men
莱恩还会死在交火中
and Lane would've been killed in the crossfire.
我不得不临时变通
I had to improvise.
那你为什么不早说
Well, why not say that in the first place?
因为我不信任你的人
Because I don't trust your people.
尤其不信任你哥哥
Especially not your brother.
家人  能拿他们怎么办呢
Family. What can you do?
那么  莱恩在哪
So, where's Lane?
显然不在塞纳河底
Certainly not at the bottom of the Seine.
他在我手上  很安全
I have him. He's safe.
我去哪儿见信使
Where do I meet the courier?
我们谈谈那个女人
Let's talk about the woman.
哪个女人
Woman?
在巴黎大皇宫时她也和你在一起
She was with you at the Palais.
佐拉今天又看到她了
Zola saw her again today.
她试图杀了莱恩
She tried to kill Lane.
她有机会杀你  但她没有下手
She had the chance to kill you, but she didn't.
为什么
Why?
我们有段过往
We have a past.
说起来很复杂
It's complicated.
我来帮你把它变得更复杂
Well, I'll make it more complicated for you.
我刚刚涨价了
My price just went up.
今天有人杀了我的四个手下
Someone killed four of my men today.
我猜是她
I'm assuming it was her.
我要她  拉克
I want her, Lark.
你要把她交给我
And you're gonna bring her to me.
否则你就见不到信使
Otherwise, you don't meet the courier
钚核会卖给出价最高者
and the plutonium goes to the highest bidder.
我不想让她成为我们之间的阻碍
I'd hate for her to come between us.
她是你的了
She's yours.
会面时交给你  之前不行
At the meeting. Not before.
去伦敦
Go to London.
随后会有指示
Instructions will follow.
我知道只要跟着她  你迟早会出现
I knew if I followed her, you'd show up eventually.
你还好吗
Are you okay?
伊尔莎  我不想伤害你的
Ilsa, I never wanted to hurt you.
我知道你有你的理由
I know you have your reasons.
我懂
I know.
你得抽身离开
You need to walk away.
我做不到
I can't do that.
-你去巴黎大皇宫不是为了杀拉克  -的确不是
- You weren't at the Palais to kill Lark. - No.
你是去保护他的
You were there to protect him.
是的
Yes.
而你为了保护我杀了他
And you killed him to protect me.
你希望拉克救出莱恩
You wanted Lark to break Lane out.
不对  你需要他救出莱恩
No, you needed him to break Lane out.
因为你必须杀了莱恩
Because you have to kill Lane.
是谁强迫你做这事的
Who's making you do this?
军情六处
MI6.
为什么
Why?
我们在伦敦抓到他后
After we captured him in London,
他们想通过外交途径将莱恩弄回国
they tried to bring Lane home through diplomatic channels.
但太多国家想要分一杯羹
But too many countries want their pound of flesh.
他这样的人  见过太多事
A man like that, what he's seen,
对英国情报局了解太多
what he knows about British Intelligence,
他们绝不能让他将信息泄露给外国政府
they can't have him talking to a foreign government ever.
我问的不是这个
That's not what I'm asking.
他们为什么派你来
Why did they send you?
这是我证明忠心的机会
This is how I prove my loyalty.
只有这样我才能真正回家
This is how I come home.
但你已经脱身了
But you were out.
你已经自由了
You were free.
我们永远都不会自由
We are never free.
我在莱恩身边卧底了两年
I spent two years undercover with Lane.
对他们来说  我和他一样是个威胁
To them, I'm as much of a threat as he is.
要么我杀了他  要么永远逃亡
I kill him, or I never stop running.
现在告诉我他在哪儿
Now tell me where he is.
我帮不了你
I can't help you.
不管怎样我都会杀了他
I will get to him one way or another.
别逼我对付你
Please don't make me go through you.
喂
Yes.
你到伦敦了吗
Are you here in London?
是的
I am.
你准备好和信使见面了吗
Are you ready to meet the courier?
准备好了  去哪见面
Yes. Where do I go?
你想去哪儿
Where would you like to meet?
定位来电
部长先生
Mr. Secretary.
我曾向上帝祈祷这不是真的
I prayed to God that it wasn't true.
我替他说句话  先生
Well, in his defense, sir,
如果伊森没有插手
if Ethan hadn't intervened,
会有更多的人被杀
a great many people would have been killed.
没错  邓恩  我相信巴黎的居民
Yes, Dunn, I'm sure that the good people of Paris
和法国全国都会考虑这一点的
and the nation of France as a whole will take that into account.
到底发生什么了
So what the hell happened?
至此  我们被告知来伦敦
...at which point, we were told to come to London
等候进一步指示
and await further instructions.
现在怎么办
And what happens now?
现在
Now,
我们20分钟后和白寡妇见面
we meet the Widow in 20 minutes.
她会带我们去见信使
She'll take us to a courier
信使会用我们丢失的钚核交换所罗门·莱恩
who'll hand over our missing plutonium in exchange for Solomon Lane.
或者按我们的方案中
Or, in our scenario,
班吉
Benji.
天啊
Jesus.
不好意思  什么
I'm sorry, what?
路德和我会把你交给信使
Luther and I are gonna take you to the courier.
沃克在这里守着真正的莱恩
Walker stays here and guards the real Lane.
绝对不行
Absolutely not.
等等  为什么非得由我扮莱恩
Wait, wait. Why do I have to be Lane?
班吉
Benji.
我们的任务  我的任务  是把钚核拿回来
Our mission, my mission, is to recover that plutonium,
我会不惜一切代价
and I will do so at any cost.
哪怕需要用莱恩做交易
Even if I have to trade Lane.
真正的莱恩
The real Lane.
我绝不会放他走
And I will never let him go.
等使徒发现你的小把戏
When the Apostles realize that you're playing games,
你就会再次失去钚核
you'll lose the plutonium. Again.
让我们来操心使徒吧
You let us worry about the Apostles.
目前我们有更严重的问题
As it stands, we have a bigger problem.
更严重的问题
A bigger problem?
-伊尔莎  -伊尔莎
- Ilsa. - Ilsa?
我们的伊尔莎  伊尔莎·浮士德
Our Ilsa? Ilsa Faust Ilsa?
她是怎么卷进来的
How is she mixed up in all of this?
她受军情六处的直接命令来杀莱恩
She's been ordered to kill Lane. Direct from MI6.
等等  巴黎那个人是她  骑摩托的
Look, wait. So that was her in Paris? On the bike.
是的
Yeah.
伊森  她想杀了我们
Ethan, she tried to kill us!
-不  不是我们  -是啊
- No, not us. Not us. - Yeah.
莱恩  她想杀的是莱恩  她别无选择
Lane. She tried to kill Lane. She has no choice.
所以她会杀了我
And she will kill me!
我不会让那发生的
I'm not gonna let that happen.
伊森  你要怎样阻止
Ethan, how exactly are you not gonna let that happen?
-我还在考虑  -他还在考虑
- I'm working on it. - Oh, he's working on it.
现在我们没时间了
Right now, we don't have a lot of time.
我们得开始为会面做准备
We have to start getting ready for this meeting.
会面是个陷阱
The meeting is a trap.
白寡妇在和中情局合作
The White Widow is working with the CIA.
从一开始就是
She has been since the beginning.
为她的军火交易争取豁免权
Bargaining for immunity is her stock-in-trade.
一网打尽钚核  使徒和约翰·拉克
Capturing the plutonium, and the Apostles, and John Lark
为她在美国人面前挣足了情面
buys her a lot of goodwill with the Americans.
但如果斯隆知道会面是陷阱
But if Sloane knew the meeting was a trap,
她为什么不直接告诉我们
why didn't she just tell us?
因为对她来说任何人都可能是约翰·拉克
Because, in her mind, anybody could be John Lark,
包括我们中的一员
including one of us.
现在她的怀疑得到了证实
And now her suspicions are confirmed.
根据这份档案
According to that dossier,
一系列的电子证据将亨特
a trail of electronic evidence connects Hunt
和疾控中心的天花盗窃联系到了一起
to the theft of smallpox from the CDC.
甚至可以将他和一段长期通信联系在一起
It also links him to a lengthy correspondence
证实是他招募了德布朗克博士
ending with the recruitment of Dr. Delbruuk.
当然了  再加上  亨特几乎是亲自
And, of course, Hunt handed over the plutonium
将钚核交到了使徒手上
to the Apostles himself.
这些事实  再结合
Now, those facts, coupled with
过去一系列不服从管控的有罪行为
a long and incriminating history of rogue behavior,
确证了中情局的一个猜想
corroborate a CIA narrative
就是亨特叛变了
that Hunt has snapped.
他对拉克的追捕不过是
And that his search for Lark is nothing but a cover
为了隐瞒拉克其实...
to hide the fact that Lark...
就是我
...is me.
我不得不佩服你  伊森
I've got to hand it to you, Ethan.
一般当人们说「你是你自己最大的敌人」时
Normally, when people refer to you as your own worst enemy,
只是一种比喻
it's just a figure of speech.
恐怕斯隆也有问题要问她
I'm afraid Sloane's got some questions for her as well.
白寡妇免费供出了她
The Widow offered her up at no extra charge.
斯隆从哪得到这些信息的
And where did Sloane get this information?
她没说
She didn't say.
不过她允许我带你自首
She did, however, grant me the opportunity to bring you in,
前提是我终止这项任务
on the condition that I terminate this mission
并亲自交出所罗门·莱恩
and hand over Solomon Lane personally.
-长官  你不能这么做  -亨特
- Sir, you can't do that. - Hunt.
我了解莱恩  他绝不想回去
I know Lane. And he has no intention of going back.
所以我们要带他回去
That's why we're taking him back.
这刚好就是他的目的
Which means that's exactly what he wants us to do.
-伊森  -长官  你觉得
- Ethan... - Sir, what do you
这是怎么回事  巧合吗
think this is? A coincidence?
有人恰巧发现了这个
That someone just happened upon this?
是莱恩寄给了她  他知道她会做出什么反应
Lane had it sent to her. He knew how she would react.
就像他知道白寡妇会出卖我们
Just like he knew the Widow would turn us in.
你还不明白吗
Don't you see?
这个  长官
This, sir...
这才是陷阱
This is the trap.
-我们在被他们操控  -亨特
- We are being directed. - Hunt!
长官  还有两个钚核下落不明
Sir, there are still two plutonium cores in the wind!
那是你弄丢的
And you lost them!
长官  公平点说  是我们丢的
In fairness, sir, we all lost them.
恕我直言  长官  你当时不在场
Respectfully, sir, you weren't there.
所以你们现在的工作就是为他找借口吗
So making excuses for him is your full-time job now?
我的天  伊森  别让这更艰难了
Good God, Ethan, don't make this any harder than it already is.
我无法再保护你了  还不明白吗
I can no longer protect you, don't you understand that?
你想拿到钚核  只能走到这一步了
This is as close as you're ever gonna get to that plutonium.
长官  你其实并不相信这个说法
Sir, you don't actually believe this.
我相信这是个可以保护你或IMF的机会
I believe I've been given a choice to protect you or the IMF,
所以我要把你带回去交给局里
which is why I'm bringing you in.
如果我拒绝呢
And if I refuse?
你以为他是来干嘛的
What do you think he's here for?
你以为他就是个旁观者
You think he's some observer?
他是个杀手
He's an assassin!
艾瑞卡·斯隆的头号打手
Erika Sloane's number-one plumber.
你要敢逃走  他有权追捕你
You go rogue, he's authorized to hunt you down
然后杀了你
and kill you.
职责而已  别见怪
It's the job. No hard feelings.
接受事实吧  伊森
Accept it, Ethan.
你这局已经输了  木已成舟  别再倔了
You've lost this one. What's done is done.
不  长官  不是的
No, sir. No.
我不是在请求  我是在给你下命令
I am not asking you. I am giving you a direct order.
本次任务终止
This mission is terminated.
立即生效
Now!
斯蒂克尔  他是你的朋友
Stickell, he's your friend.
能拜托你好好劝他...
Would you please talk some sense into...
抱歉  长官  但你让我别无选择
I'm sorry, sir, but you left me no choice.
我们还有15分钟就要去见白寡妇
There's 15 minutes before we meet the Widow.
你想要钚核  只有我们
You want the plutonium, we're the only ones
能帮你拿到  你选择入不入伙吗
who can get it for you. You in or out?
入
In.
-你在干什么  -班吉得去准备了
- What are you doing? - Benji needs to get ready.
-不行  伊森  -没时间了  路德
- No, Ethan... - There's no time, Luther.
我需要你信任我
I need you to trust me.
你还好吗
You all right?
还好  就是...
Yeah, I just...
有种不祥的预感
got a bad feeling about this one.
如果没有我们的消息...
If you don't hear from us...
我会按我的方法来
I'll do it my way.
把他盯紧了
Don't take your eyes off him.
不用继续演了  我带你离开
Enough games. I'm taking you out of here.
亨特在哪儿
Where's Hunt?
他带着你的替身去见白寡妇了
He's gone to the meeting, with a copy of you.
冷静点
Calm down.
呼叫使徒  提醒他们
Call the Apostles. Warn them.
我不知道怎么联系他们
I have no way of contacting them.
出于我们双方的安全考虑
For their safety and mine.
我只有一支撤离小队
What I do have is an extraction team with
正在进行卫星监视  并提前定好了集合地点
satellite overwatch and a prearranged rendezvous.
我们一离开他们就会知道
They'll know as soon as we leave the building.
不  我要留在这里
No, I'm staying here.
我和亨特的事还没了结
I haven't finished with Hunt yet.
你为什么要把事情搞得这么复杂
Why did you have to make this so fucking complicated?
我不懂你的意思
I don't understand what you mean.
当初的交易很简单
The deal was simple.
我帮你陷害亨特  你把钚核给我
I help you frame Hunt, you give me the plutonium.
你这是在浪费时间
You're wasting time.
"所有的和平  都需要伟大的牺牲
"There cannot be peace without first a great suffering.
牺牲越大  和平越久"
"The greater the suffering, the greater the peace."
我写这些话的时候
When I wrote those words,
指的可不是你的和平  或亨特的牺牲
I wasn't referring to your peace or Hunt's suffering.
旧世界的秩序需要被废除
The old world order needs dismantling,
而我们有可以实现这一点的工具
and we have the tools to dismantle it.
而你似乎只关心
All you seem to care about
让亨特背负罪责活下去
is that Hunt lives to take the blame.
你这不是无政府主义
That's not anarchy.
而是报复
That's revenge.
没错
Yes, it is.
当我如愿以偿时
And when I have what I want,
使徒会把钚核给你
the Apostles will give you the plutonium.
亨特是你唯一的朋友
Hunt's the only friend you've got.
你能活到今天
You're only alive today
是因为他下不了狠心杀你
because he didn't have the guts to kill you.
斯隆说得对  IMF就是过家家
Sloane was right. The IMF is Halloween.
不过就是几个成年人戴着...
Nothing but grown men wearing...
怎么了
What?
职责而已  别见怪
It's just the job. No hard feelings.
我破坏了你的好日子  是吗
I've ruined your day, haven't I?
你在此之前都伪装得天衣无缝
And you were doing so well up until then.
我看这一支才有子弹
Now, I think this one's loaded.
你想试试吗
You want to find out?
-我演得怎么样  -我从未有过半分疑虑
- So, how'd I do? - I never had a doubt.
我开始明白你们为什么喜欢这么玩了
I'm beginning to see why you guys enjoy this so much.
过奖  部长先生
Hats off, Mr. Secretary.
-那家伙是天生好手  -欢迎加入  长官
- The man's a natural. - Welcome to the team, sir.
你们这是在犯错
You're making a mistake.
不  犯错的是我  我不该在巴黎救你
No, the mistake was mine when I saved your life over Paris.
这证明不了什么  我是在演戏
This proves nothing. I'm playing a role,
就跟你们一样  都是为了拿回钚核
just like you are, trying to recover that plutonium.
这还是无法解释你为什么要给斯隆那份档案
That doesn't explain why you gave Sloane the dossier
试图陷害亨特
and tried to frame Hunt.
他说得有道理
He makes a good point,
拉克
Lark.
他有妄想症  精神紊乱
He's paranoid. Delusional.
正如档案里写的一样
Just like the dossier says.
那斯隆是从哪拿到了这份档案
So where did Sloane get the dossier from?
我不知道
I have no idea.
我知道
I do.
你都听到了吧  艾瑞卡
Did you get all that, Erika?
是的
I did.
我不喜欢被利用  沃克
I don't appreciate being used, Walker.
哎呦  闯祸了
Oops. Bad boy.
你想要把他送到哪
Where would you like him delivered?
我会去找你
I'll come to you.
都不许动  都不许动
Nobody move! Nobody move!
放下武器  都放下
Weapons down! Drop 'em!
举起手来  放下武器
Hands in the air! Weapons down!
放下  放下
Drop it! Drop it!
放下武器  快点  你
Weapons down! Right now! You!
没事  没事  没事的
It's okay. It's okay. It's all right. It's all right.
我们不是说好了吗
I thought we had a deal.
之前是  现在没了
We did. And now we don't.
现在的风险太高  我可不敢冒险
There is too much at stake here for me to take any chances.
我要把你们和沃克一起带走
I'm bringing you all in, along with Walker.
钚核还流落在外
The plutonium is still out there!
但我却无法放心让你们任何一人去拿回钚核
And I don't trust a living soul in that room to get it.
我们会在华盛顿弄清楚你们的身份
We'll sort out who's who in Washington.
-艾瑞卡  -长官
- Erika! - Sir?
没关系  我们就照她说的做
It's all right. Let's just do what she says.
真正的威胁都在这里  都在我们手里了
The only real threats are in this room, and we have them.
是吗
Do you?
动手
Go.
莱恩跑哪去了
Where the hell is Lane?
伊森  伊森
Ethan! Ethan!
第一队都倒下了  派后援来
First team is down. Send backup.
长官
Sir!
不  不  有人受伤  有人受伤
Oh, no, no, no. Man down! Man down!
谁来帮帮忙
Somebody help!
长官
Sir.
伊森  我给沃克注射了追踪器  但他跑了
Ethan, I tagged Walker, but he's on the run.
你得去抓到他
You got to get him.
去吧
Go.
抱歉  长官
I'm sorry, sir.
去吧
Go.
伊森
Ethan?
等等
Wait!
去抓回那个狗娘养的
Get that son of a bitch.
快啊  快啊  快啊
Come on, come on, come on.
棒  我定位到他了
Yes! I got him.
不好意思
I'm sorry.
告诉我  班吉  沃克在哪
Talk to me, Benji. Where's Walker?
你向右转  他在你西方约400米处
He's about a quarter mile west if you turn right.
向右转吗
To my right?
我没办法过去
I can't do that.
为什么不行
Why not?
因为我被盯上了
Because I'm being followed.
什么意思  被谁
What do you mean? By who?
我怎么知道  中情局或是使徒
How do I know? CIA, Apostles...
有什么区别吗
What difference does it make?
好吧  好吧  那就赶紧离开  然后右转
Okay, okay, just get out of there and then go right.
我非常抱歉
I am terribly sorry.
请原谅我
Excuse me.
他为什么在绕圈
Why is he running in circles?
好了  你需要尽快穿过左边的街道
Okay, you need to cross the street on your left as soon as you can.
伊森  你收到了吗
Ethan, did you copy?
-左边  快左转  -我在努力了
- Left, go left, now! - I'm working on it.
现在穿过你前方的街道
Now go across the street right in front of you.
伊森  他正在远离你  你得快一点
Ethan, he's getting away from you! You're gonna have to go faster.
你要追上他了  直走
You're gaining on him! Go straight.
直走  一直走吗
Straight? Keep going straight?
直走  直走  直走
Go straight, go straight, straight, straight.
好  现在右转
Okay, now turn right.
右
Right?
现在吗
Now?
-是  右转  -你确定吗
- Yes, right! - Are you sure?
确定  我
Yes, I'm...
不  是左边  左转
No, it's left! Turn left!
抱歉  刚才屏幕旋转被锁定了
Sorry, I had the screen-lock on.
左
Left.
谢谢
Thank you.
-你还在等什么  -我可是要跳窗
- What are you waiting for? - I'm jumping out a window!
你说什么呢  你要跳...
What do you mean, you're jumping out of a...
抱歉  刚才是平面图
Sorry. I had it in 2D.
祝你好运
Good luck.
到桥的尽头左转  你快追上他了
At the end of the bridge, turn left. You've almost got him.
加油  加油  加油  伊森  抓到他
Come on, come on, come on. Come on, Ethan, get him!
你就在他上方不远处
You're right on top of him!
好了  他就在你前方
That's it, he's right in front of you!
抓住他  抓住他  抓住他
Get him! Get him! Get him!
你不能开枪  对吧  你还没拿到钚核
You can't do it, can you? Not until you get your plutonium.
是啊  他对你还有其他安排
No. He still has plans for you.
你要去自首  承认你就是约翰·拉克
You're gonna turn yourself in and admit you're John Lark,
然后在你的小牢房里看着旧世界被毁灭
then watch the old world implode from your dark little cell.
如果我不去呢
And if I don't?
我是她的守护天使  亨特
I'm her guardian angel, Hunt.
再让我看到你  她就会死
If I see you again, she dies.
如果你试图提醒她  她也会死
If you try to warn her, she dies.
该认输的时候就认输
Know when you're beat.
这些是我们从德布朗克博士
These are the designs we recovered
在柏林的实验室里找到的
from Dr. Delbruuk's lab in Berlin.
那是个5兆吨的核装置
That's a five-megaton nuclear device.
比二战中释放的总爆炸能量都要高
That's greater than all the explosive energy released in World War II.
要拆除的话  通常得剪断这根引信
To disarm it, normally we'd cut the fuse wire here.
"通常"是什么意思
What, "normally"?
沃克和莱恩有两个钚核
Walker and Lane have two plutonium cores,
也就是两个核弹
meaning two bombs.
没错  它们都连接着微波故障保护
Yeah. And they're both linked by a microwave fail-safe
精确度在0.1秒内
which is accurate to within one-tenth of a second.
若试图拆除一枚核弹  会自动引爆另一枚
Any attempt to defuse one bomb automatically triggers the other.
意味着核弹一经安装  无法拆除
Meaning once armed, the bombs cannot be disarmed.
倒计时由一个远程引爆器开启
The countdown is started by a remote detonator,
它也有故障保护
which is also a fail-safe.
意味着一旦开始倒计时
Meaning once the countdown starts,
就无法停止
it can't be stopped.
所以解决办法是....
So the solution to this is?
我们还在研究
We're working on it.
所以
So,
严格来讲  这就是一次自杀式任务
technically, this is a suicide mission.
怎么了
What is it?
坐吧  请
Have a seat. Please.
我认识了伊森那么多年
In all the years that I've known Ethan,
只见过他对两个女人动真情
he's only been serious about two women.
一个是他的妻子
One was his wife.
他结婚了
He's married?
不  是曾经结过
No, he was.
曾经  她出了什么事
Was? What happened to her?
一群坏人把她抓走了  以此要挟伊森
Well, she was taken by some people who wanted to get to Ethan.
没事  他把她安然无恙地救回来了
It's okay, he got her back in one piece.
然后他就金盆洗手了
Then he quit the game.
他们度过了一段幸福的时光
They were happy for a while.
但每次世界上有不幸的事发生
But every time something bad happened in the world,
伊森都会认为  "我该去帮忙的"
Ethan would think, "I should've been there."
她也会自问  "伊森在保护我
And she would wonder, "Who's watching the world
那谁来保护世界"
while Ethan's watching me?"
他们内心深处都知道  迟早有一天
Deep down, they both knew that someday, somehow,
会有不可挽回的惨剧发生
something truly terrible was going to happen
就因为他们在一起
all because they were together.
所以...
So...
-她现在在哪儿  -她行踪成谜
- Where is she now? - She's a ghost.
她很擅长隐藏
Good at it, too.
是我亲自教她的
Taught her myself.
她偶尔会发送信号
Every now and then, she sends up a signal
让伊森知道她平安无事
to let Ethan know she's safe.
那让他安心地继续战斗
And that keeps him going.
你为什么告诉我这个
Why are you telling me this?
我们身陷现在的困境
We're in this mess
都是因为伊森不愿看着我死
because Ethan wouldn't let me die.
他...他是个好人
He...He's a good man.
他或许嘴上不说  但他实际上非常在乎你
And he cares about you more than he can admit.
他现在无暇分神去为你操心
That's one more worry than he can handle right now.
如果你也在乎他
If you care about him,
你就该离开
you should walk away.
路德
Luther...
没出什么事吧
Is everything all right?
我跟你一起去
I'm coming with you.
我懂
I know.
我们如何找到他
So how do we find him?
微波收发器
Microwave transponder.
能通过卫星追踪到世界上任何一个角落
Traceable via satellite anywhere in the world.
莱恩后颈上就有一个
Lane had one of these in the back of his neck.
我们在巴黎时给取出来了
We removed it in Paris.
同时  把我们的收发器装了进去
At the same time, we put our own transponder in.
搞定
Got it.
36小时后才激活
36-hour delayed activation,
以防莱恩的使徒扫描他
in case Lane's Apostles scan him.
所以你们是故意放他走的
So you planned on letting him go.
不是以这种方式  不过是的
Not this way, but yes.
他会领着我们找到钚核
He's gonna lead us to the plutonium.
你如何能确定
How can you be sure?
他陷害我坐牢的计划失败了
His plan to put me in prison went to hell.
现在他会想让我亲眼看到结局
Now he's gonna want me there for the end.
那收发器什么时候激活
So when does this transponder activate?
找到他了  找到他了  找到他了
I got him. I got him, I got him, I got him!
他正在欧洲以五百节速度向东移动
He's traveling east over Europe at 500 knots.
他在飞机上
He's airborne.
我们要通知中情局吗
Shall we inform the CIA?
中情局已经被渗透了
The CIA's been infiltrated.
除了这房间里的人  我不信任任何人
I don't trust anybody outside of this room.
我们必须独立行动
We're gonna have to go it alone.
我们该去哪儿
So where do we go?
克什米尔
情况如何  班吉
How we doing, Benji?
如果有拆除这些炸弹的方法  我找不到
If there's a way to defuse these bombs, I can't find it.
你会想到办法的  我相信你
You'll figure it out. I know you will.
无信号
该死  伊森  我们失去信号了
Damn. Ethan, we lost the signal.
莱恩一定是发现了我们的信号发射器
Lane must've found our transmitter.
他最后的已知位置在哪儿
What's his last position?
离这里东北方向30英里
At about 30 miles northeast.
那里就是他要我们去的目的地
Then that's where he wants us to go.
-那里有什么  -努布拉河谷
- What's there? - The Nubra River Valley.
那个范围内只有一个医疗营地
There's only a medical camp there.
海外人道主义援助
Humanitarian Aid Overseas.
莱恩为什么要袭击一个医疗营地
Why would Lane target a medical camp?
天花
Smallpox.
-什么  -天花
- What? - Smallpox.
他的使徒曾在克什米尔引起天花爆发
The Apostles triggered a smallpox outbreak in Kashmir.
莱恩把营地安排到那里一定是有原因的
Lane must've wanted that camp there for a reason.
但具体是什么
But what?
-天啊  -怎么了
- Oh, my God. - What is it?
努布拉河就在锡亚琴冰川的山脚下
The Nubra River is at the base of the Siachen Glacier.
一次核爆炸会使
So a nuclear blast there would irradiate
全球最大的自然灌溉系统遭受辐射
the largest natural irrigation system in the world.
从中国边境流入印度和巴基斯坦的淡水都会被污染
Fresh water from the border of China to India and Pakistan.
他们要饿死全球三分一的人口
They're gonna starve one-third of the world's population.
"牺牲越大"
"The greater the suffering..."
"和平越久"
"...the greater the peace."
我还是不明白
I still don't understand
莱恩为什么要把一个医疗营地弄到那儿
why Lane wants a medical camp there.
那不重要
It doesn't matter.
现在当务之急是找到拆除炸弹的方法
All that matters now is we find a way to defuse those bombs.
我想我找到了
I think I've found it.
或许吧
Maybe.
你看  炸弹的操作系统似乎有漏洞
Look, there appears to be a flaw in the bomb's operating system.
远程引爆器需要那个引爆键
The remote detonator requires that firing key.
拆除那个键  应该能让保险装置短路
If we remove that key, then it should short out the fail-safe
然后我们就可以剪断引信
and allow us to cut both fuses.
这么说我们中得有人拿到引爆器
So one of us needs to get the detonator
-拆除引爆键  -没错
- and remove that key. - Yeah.
同时其他人去把两个炸弹的引信剪断
While the rest of us cut the fuses on both bombs.
很简单
Simple.
没错  但是...
Yeah, but...
但是什么
But what?
这办法要想奏效
Well, in order to make this work,
必须等到爆炸倒计时开始后
we can't remove the key or cut the fuses
再拆除引爆键  剪断引信
until after the countdown starts.
等等  我理清楚一下
But wait, just so I've got this clear.
我们安全拆除炸弹的唯一方法
Our only chance to safely defuse both bombs
是让爆炸倒计时开始
is to let the countdown start.
然后再拆除引爆键
And then remove that key.
好吧
Okay.
两个爆炸装置都已跟引爆器接通
Both devices are now connected to the detonator.
15分钟应该足以让你转移到
Fifteen minutes should give you enough time
最小安全距离
to reach minimum safe distance.
我逃亡的日子结束了
My running days are over.
这里就是我的终点
This is where it ends for me.
这里到处都是信号
I'm getting signals all over the place.
我们在医疗营地里
We're at a medical camp.
到处都是X光机  造影扫描仪
X-ray machines, CAT scanners,
和放射性设备
radiological signatures everywhere.
这样仿佛大海捞针
It's like a needle in a haystack.
用排除法  一个一个找
Process of elimination, one at a time.
我们分头行事  保持联络
Let's split up. Stay on comms.
伊森
Ethan?
茱莉亚
Julia?
那是...
Is that...
茱莉亚
Julia!
他知道吗
Does he know?
这位是我丈夫  艾瑞克
This is my husband, Erik.
这位是...
This is...
罗伯·索恩  罗伯·索恩医生
Rob. Rob Thorne. Dr. Rob Thorne.
-我曾与茱莉亚...  -在麻省总医院共事
- I worked with Julia... - At Mass General.
在去纽约之前
Before New York.
真不敢相信
You're kidding.
-好巧啊  -就是啊
- What a coincidence! - I know. I...
-你怎么会跑到这么偏僻的地方来  -我...
- What brings you all this way? - I was, uh...
我之前在附近的塔图克村
I was in Turtuk, not far from here
听说这里需要人手
and heard help was needed.
实际上  我们在这里的工作快完成了
Actually, we're just about finished here.
整个村庄都接种疫苗了  不过...
The whole village is inoculated. But, um...
你到塔图克做什么
What were you doing out in Turtuk?
罗伯在度假
Rob's on vacation.
不  不  我是为工作而来
No. No, I'm... I'm working.
你们离家很远啊
You're a long way from home.
是啊  多亏了我们的守护天使
Yeah, yeah. Thanks to our guardian angel.
守护天使
Guardian?
是啊  这里疫情爆发时  我们正在
Well, yeah. We were running a field hospital
苏丹达尔富尔边界运营战地医院
outside of Darfur when the outbreak happened here.
我们突然接到
And here comes this phone call
一位匿名捐赠人的电话
from an anonymous donor, out of the blue.
他说他要支付整个行动的费用
And he says he's ready to underwrite the entire operation.
只有一个条件
One condition.
就是由我们来管理
We run the whole thing.
你敢相信吗
Can you believe that?
我可以相信
I certainly can.
是啊  毫无预兆
Yeah. Out of the blue.
毫无预兆
Out of the blue.
这样的生活很充实丰富
That's quite a full life.
是啊  认识茱莉亚之前  我从不出远门
Yeah, you know, before Julia, I never traveled.
我连纽约都没离开过
I never even left New York.
整天待在医院里
Never left the hospital.
一周工作七天  没日没夜  从不休假
Seven days a week, dusk till dawn. No vacations.
伊森  我好像有所发现
Ethan, I think I found something.
照那个速度  我50岁就能当上外科主任
I was on the fast track to be Chief of Surgery at 50.
55岁就会心脏病发
Heart attack at 55.
但是她说服我放下那一切
And she convinced me to let it all go.
到最需要帮助的地方
Help where it's needed most.
从那以后我们一直在外奔波
So we've been on the go ever since,
我的人生从未像现在这般充实满足
and I've never been more fulfilled.
我替你们高兴
I'm happy for you.
谢谢
Thank you.
我们该走了
Well, we should get going.
有很多东西要收拾打包
We have a lot of packing to do.
不  我去弄就好  你们叙叙旧
Oh, no, I'll handle that. You two should catch up.
不  我就不打扰你们了
Oh, no, I should get out of your hair.
开什么玩笑  你应该逗留一阵
Are you kidding? You should stick around.
我只是很遗憾你白跑了一趟
I'm just sorry you came all this way for nothing.
不如这样吧  我们收拾好行李
Tell you what, we'll pack,
然后开车送你回图塔克
and why don't we give you a ride back to Turtuk,
你们可以在车上叙叙旧  怎么样
you two can catch up in the car? Yeah?
你太客气了
You're very kind.
就这么定了  待会儿见
Settled. See you soon.
见到你很高兴
It was good to see you.
对不起  茱莉亚  对不起
I am so sorry, Julia. I'm so sorry.
两架直升机都开走
Take both helicopters.
断掉其他所有人离开的路
No one else leaves.
小心点  小心点
Careful, careful, careful.
炸弹已装上
It's armed.
但倒计时还未开始
But the countdown hasn't started yet.
网络信号很强  说明另一个爆炸装置
The network signal's strong, which means the other device
和引爆器也在附近
is close by and the detonator.
大概在那个方向  离这里半公里处
About half a K in that direction.
他们还在这儿
They're still here.
路德  你继续处理爆炸装置
Luther, you keep working on it.
你们两个跟我来
You two, come with me.
没问题  我能行
Sure. I got this.
不用担心老路德
Don't worry about old Luther.
正在扫描...
是沃克
Walker.
已连接上
该死
Damn.
伊森  倒计时开始了
Ethan, the countdown has started!
我们只有15分钟的时间
We have 15 minutes.
引爆器在沃克手上
Walker has the detonator.
快点  快点
Come on, come on!
我们得疏散这些人
We have to evacuate these people.
没时间了
There's no time.
15分钟后  整个河谷都会被烧成灰烬
This whole valley's gonna be incinerated in 15 minutes.
已经太迟了
It's too late!
不
No.
我会拿到引爆器
I'm gonna get the detonator.
-什么  怎么做  -我会想到办法的
- What? How? - I'll figure it out.
找到莱恩和另一枚炸弹
Find Lane! Find the other bomb!
-他到底在干什么  -我觉得最好别看
- What the hell is he doing? - I find it best not to look.
路德  情况如何
How we doing, Luther?
到处都是绊线  我只有两只手
Tripwires everywhere. I don't have enough hands.
想办法解决
Just make it happen.
伊森在哪儿
Where's Ethan?
他去追引爆器了
He's gone after the detonator.
等等  引爆器在哪儿
Wait, where's the detonator?
路德
Luther.
茱莉亚  你不该来的
Julia. You shouldn't be here.
我的天
Oh, my God.
那是我认为的那东西吗
Is that what I think it is?
路德  把她弄走
Luther, get her out of there!
她能去哪里
Where is she gonna go?
我能做些什么
What can I do?
工具箱里有个红色手柄的钳子
In the kit, the pliers with the red grip.
-你疯了吗  -管好你自己的事  班吉
- Are you insane? - Mind your business, Benji.
这就是我自己的事
This is my business!
班吉  能听见吗
Benji, do you copy?
伊森  伊森  你在哪
Ethan! Ethan, where are you?
我在直升机上追沃克
I'm in a helicopter going after Walker.
等一下
Hold on.
你怎么进到直升机里的
How did you get in the helicopter?
你会开直升飞机吗
What, you can fly a helicopter?
你刚才是说直升机吗
Did you say helicopter?
你跑到直升机里搞什么
What the hell are you doing in a helicopter?
我...只是  你们找到另外一枚炸弹没有
Just... Hey, hey... Did you find the other bomb?
我们还在找  不过即使找到了
We're still looking, but finding the bomb
也没什么用  除非拿到引爆装置
is not gonna matter unless we have the detonator.
我知道  我知道  我保证拿到它
I know. I know. I'll get it. I'll get it!
不过  他人在另一架直升机里
Uh, if he's in another helicopter,
-你要怎么拿到  -我会想到办法的
- how are you gonna get it? - I'll figure it out.
你们找到炸弹  我来搞定引爆装置
You find the bomb, I'll get the detonator.
我不会让你们失望的
I won't let you down.
不会让你们失望的
-准备好  -你听好  伊森
- Be ready. - Look, Ethan. Ethan!
呼叫伊森
Ethan, come in!
班吉  班吉  路德
Benji? Benji? Luther?
有人能听见吗
Anybody?
我能做到  我能做到
I can do this. I can do this.
这都是些什么
What do we got here?
这里有空速表
We've got airspeed.
空速表
Airspeed.
好的  动力  这是动力装置
Okay, power. This is power.
载荷  怎么才能把这个载荷卸掉
Payload. How do I get rid of this payload?
加大动力
Power.
把剥皮钳拿来
Wire strippers.
我是医生  不是电工
I'm a doctor, not an electrician.
抱歉  拿一下绿手柄的那个
Sorry, the thing with the green grip.
-拿到了  -剪我左手这根线
- Got it. - The wire in my left hand.
-黑线吗  -左手这根
- The black one? - My left hand.
-你左手这根就是黑的啊  -抱歉  剪另一根
- That's your left hand. - Sorry, the other wire.
红线吗
The red one?
没错  我右手的红线
Yes, the red one in my right hand.
只是确认下
Just checking.
我喜欢她
Oh, I like her.
一定要砸中啊
Hold this for me, will you?
我操
Holy shit!
该死的
Damn it!
飞到上面去
Get up there!
没错就是我  混蛋
That's right, prick.
我操
Oh, shit!
混蛋
Son of a bitch.
好吧
All right.
太过了  太猛了
Whoa, whoa, too much. Too much.
我操
Oh, shit!
拉升  拉升
Pull up. Pull up.
接近地面  请拉升
Terrain. Terrain. Pull up.
请拉升
Pull up.
我在努力  在努力提升了
I'm trying, I'm trying!
接近地面  接近地面
Terrain. Terrain.
班吉  我什么都找不到
Benji, I'm not finding anything.
我觉得我们找错地方了
I think we're looking in the wrong place.
到处都是信号
Signatures everywhere.
这真是藏炸弹的完美地点
This is the perfect place to hide it.
就是为了这样  我了解莱恩
That's the point. I know Lane.
如果我们在这里一直找
If we're looking here,
那就正中他的下怀
it's because he wants us to.
我去村子里找
I'm heading to the village.
等等我  好吗
Just wait for me, all right?
伊尔莎  我感觉我找到什么了
Ilsa, I think I've found something.
从这里把线剪断
Cut this wire right here.
逆时针拧开螺丝  慢慢地
Turn that screw counterclockwise, very slowly.
明白
Got it.
所以
So...
他怎么样
How is he?
你懂的  还是老样子
Oh, you know. Same old Ethan.
老天
Jesus!
糟了
Oh, shit!
不不不  不要啊
No, no, no, no, no, no.
班吉  我看到莱恩了
Benji, I see Lane.
什么  哪里
What? Where?
他在村子边缘的一栋房子里
He's in a house at the edge of the village.
好吧  等着我  行吗
All right, just wait for me, okay?
伊尔莎  等等我
Ilsa, wait for me!
不行
No.
是核弹可怎么办
Nuclear bomb.
小心X射线辐射
该死
Damn it!
班吉  我找到另一枚炸弹了
Benji, I found the other bomb.
伊尔莎  你在哪里
Ilsa, where are you?
我在一间房子里
I'm in a house...
喂  你在干什么呢
Hey! What the hell are you doing?
你疯了吧
You're out of your mind!
我都不知道下面有什么
I don't know what's down there.
拉升  快拉升
Pull up, pull up!
这个狗娘养的疯子打算撞死我们
This crazy son of a bitch is trying to ram us!
开快点
Go!
操
Shit!
呼叫班吉
Benji, come in.
我们就快拆到引信了
We're almost at the fuse.
得赶紧找到另一枚炸弹
We need to find that other bomb now.
你刚刚是说另一枚炸弹吗
Did you just say "other bomb"?
-班吉  听见了吗  -我正在找
- Benji, do you read me? - I'm working on it!
伊尔莎  你在哪里
Ilsa, where are you?
你阻止不了的
You can't stop it.
明白吗  他什么也做不了
Do you understand? There's nothing he can do.
等时间一到
When the clock runs out,
伊森·亨特就会失去一切东西
Ethan Hunt will lose everything
以及他在乎的每一个人
and everyone he ever cared about.
伊尔莎
Ilsa!
班吉
Benji!
伊尔莎  你在哪儿
Ilsa, where are you?
你不会想看到这一幕的
You don't want to see this.
班吉
Benji!
-伊尔莎  -班吉
- Ilsa! - Benji!
班吉  班吉  别过来
Benji! Benji, stop!
班吉
Benji!
不  不要
Oh, no, no, no!
稳住  稳住
Stay with me. Stay with me.
不要  我就快要成功了  坚持住
No, no. Not when I'm this close.
拜托  拜托
Come on, come on!
谢了
Thank you.
把他捆起来
Tie him up.
你给我去死吧
Why won't you just die?
你也帮不上什么忙了
There's nothing else you can do.
去找你的丈夫吧
Go be with your husband.
路德
Luther...
去吧
Go.
班吉  你在哪儿
Benji, where are you?
路德  我们在屋里  接下来怎么办
Okay, Luther, we're inside. Tell us what to do.
你们应该能看见连着主板的红线
You should see the red wire attached to the motherboard.
是的
Yeah.
把它和旁边的绿线同时剪断
You need to cut that and the green wire next to it simultaneously.
-好  准备好了吗  -嗯
- Okay, ready? - Mmm-hmm.
预备  剪
Set. Go.
我说了  那是无可阻止的
I told you. It can't be stopped.
你们什么也做不了
There's nothing you can do.
班吉  听好  逆时针拧开螺丝
Benji, listen. Turn the screw counterclockwise.
好
Yep.
移开表盘  你会看到
Remove that panel and you'll see
电源和引信的地线
the power and ground wires for the fuse.
明白
Got it.
时间一到就剪绿线
When the time comes, cut the green wire.
现在别剪
Do not cut it yet.
好的  收到
Okay. We copy.
伊森  你能听到我说话吗  我们要剪了
Ethan, if you can hear me, we're ready to make the cut.
伊森  请回答
Ethan, come in.
班吉  我们怎么知道他拿没拿到引爆键
Benji, how do we know if he's got the key?
他会拿到的
He'll get it.
-就算是  我们怎么知道  -他一定能搞定
- Yeah, but how do we know? - He'll get it done!
就快没时间了  只能希望他拿到了
We're out of time. We just have to hope he has it.
-好  准备好了  -剩两秒时剪下去
- Okay, we're ready. - At two seconds we cut.
等一下  为什么是两秒  不是一秒
Wait, wait, wait! Why two? Why not one?
你要把时间卡那么紧吗
You want to cut it that close?
那一秒可能会万劫不复  无法弥补
It's a second we'll never get back.
到底什么时候  能赶快做个决定吗
When? Can we make a decision on this?
好  好  剩一秒再剪
All right, all right! We'll do it on one.
一秒的时候吗
Cutting on one?
没错  一秒  好了  准备
Yes, one. All right, stand by.
三
Three...
-二  -一
- Two... - One.
剪
Now!
好了
Okay.
老天啊
My man.
伊森
Ethan?
能听见吗
Can you hear me?
别动
Don't try to move.
别动  你伤得很重
Don't move. You're pretty banged up.
你可够走运的
You're a lucky man.
坠机还没死真是奇迹啊  索恩医生
It's a miracle that crash didn't kill you, Dr. Thorne.
你朋友要是再晚一小时找到你
If your friend didn't find you an hour later,
你就要死在爆炸里了
you would've died of exposure.
-我朋友  -是啊
- My friends? - Yeah.
你走之后没多久她就来了
She got here not long after you left.
还搬来了半个印度军队
Right in front of half the Indian Army.
能让我们单独待一会吗
Can you give us a few minutes, please?
回头见  医生
See you later, Doc.
茱莉亚
Julia...
对不起
I'm sorry.
你不需要向我道歉
There's no reason to be sorry.
不
No.
真的对不起
I'm sorry
为所有的事  我...
for everything. I...
你看看我
Look at me.
看看我
再看看我的生活
Look at my life.
我热爱我的事业  如果不是遇到你
I love what I do, and I never would have
我永远也意识不到这一点
found this if I hadn't met you.
所有发生过的事  都让我认清我是怎样一个人
And everything that happened, it taught me who I am.
让我明白自身的能力  我...
It showed me what I am capable of, and I...
我是个幸存者
I am a survivor.
但这里发生的事
But what happened here,
-都是因为我...  -没有发生任何事
- it was my... - Nothing happened.
因为有你在
Because you were here.
每晚我能安然入睡  也是因为知道你一直在
And I sleep soundly at night knowing you always will be.
你幸福吗
You're happy?
非常幸福
Very.
我找到了我命中注定的归属
I'm exactly where I should be.
你也是
And so are you.
应你的要求
Per your request,
我将把所罗门·莱恩交给军情六处
I'm handing Solomon Lane back to MI6.
当然  要经由中间人
Through a broker, of course.
那也是我们协议中的一部分
Part of our ongoing arrangement.
经过巴黎的事情之后
After what happened in Paris,
我们希望能保持低调
we prefer to keep a low profile.
你朋友和英国情报机构的旧账也一笔勾销
And that closes your friend's account with British Intelligence.
肋骨疼  小心我的肋骨
The ribs. Watch the ribs.
我现在明白为什么汉利那么信任你了
I understand now why Hunley believed in you.
世界需要IMF
The world needs the IMF.
我们需要你这样的人
We need people like you
对个体性命的在乎程度
who care about the one life
和对千百万人性命的在乎程度一样
as much as they care about the millions.
那样我就不需要操心了
That way I never have to.
你还好吗
You okay?
你现在真是前所未有得帅
You've never looked better.
拜托  别取笑我了
Don't. Please.
最后一刻有多危急
How close were we?
和平常一样
The usual.
和平常一样吗
The usual?
别逗我笑了
Please don't make me laugh.